<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashok Koyi</title>
    <description>Founder @ 1Ton Technologies</description>
    <link>https://thekalinga.in/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://thekalinga.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 01:02:57 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 01:02:57 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Self Certification &amp; Wrong Diagnosis</title>
        <description>
          
          
          <![CDATA[
            <img src="https://thekalinga.in/2022/12/25/self-certification-wrong-diagnosis/anarchy-scaled.jpeg" alt="Self Certification & Wrong Diagnosis" >
            <p><img src="anarchy-scaled.jpeg" alt="Self Certification &amp; Wrong Diagnosis" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" />
<em>Image credit:</em> <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/qqiAxa9hpaA">A black anarchy graffity on a white house wall.</a></p>

<p>I came across <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20221223072059/https://www.outlookindia.com/national/why-the-recent-attack-on-judiciary-is-absolutely-uncalled-for-magazine-246901">this article</a> written by a former Indian Supreme Court Judge. The thrust of his argument is Government (Executive branch) of Indian State is attempting to undermine Judges (Judicial branch) by publicly making adverse comments against Judiciary &amp; author says this is wrong.</p>

<p>This made me think about an irritating &amp; infectious disease I see pervasive throughout Indian society, especially amongst our ruling class — one of <em>self-certification</em>. This “culture”/irritating disease of giving self-certificates or getting certificates from ones buddies (buddy-certificates) or getting certificates from one’s subordinates<sup id="fnref:masturbation-circle-jerk-bdsm"><a href="#fn:masturbation-circle-jerk-bdsm" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, has become more or less a second nature to our ruling class. Once someone treads this path of self-certification (from now on, I will use <em>self-certification</em> to mean all 3 mechanisms I just described), one will skip over foundational issues, arrives at a wrong diagnosis &amp; ultimately proposes solutions that drive them to incorrect destination.</p>

<p>Pick any section of ruling class/ruling class-adjacent — Executive/Government (Police, Army, …), Legislature, Judiciary, Election Commission, “Journalists”, Lawyers, Capitalists, Entertainers (or) any group that can exercise authority in any manner; most of them give self-certificates. Incase of Executive &amp; Judiciary, if any critic commits the “crime” of having heterodox opinion about these BS certificates, expresses their contempt openly in a concrete &amp; visible manner — thanks to World’s Best Constitution™<sup id="fnref:worlds-best-constitution"><a href="#fn:worlds-best-constitution" class="footnote">2</a></sup> we have in India — they can [&amp; often will] be “legally” terrorised with a credible threat to critic’s liberty/property/person. In case of other groupings, they will “legally” harass (or) shun them by denying access &amp; make the critic an outcast.</p>

<h2 id="legitimacy">Legitimacy</h2>

<p>Let’s take a look at the legitimacy of Judicial Bureaucrats &amp; Executive/Legislature in India.</p>

<p>What legitimacy does a Judicial bureaucratic wing has, which none of us ever agreed is a neutral arbitrator, in adjudicating all our disputes — affecting ~1.4 billion people?</p>

<p>How about Executive/Legislative wings?</p>

<p>Does forcing people to press a button [in voting machine] once every 5yrs amounts to people giving informed consent? Aren’t these “elections” in our so-called “Democracy” nothing but sham exercises in which most/all of us are coerced to certify the transfer of power from one faction of ruling class to another faction of ruling class — even if we dont want to give up power — with our role curtailed to mere button pressing [in voting machine]/checking a box [in ballot paper] &amp; STFU?</p>

<p>Does a system in which we barely have any say (in reality almost none) in how its actually run have any legitimacy?</p>

<p>With that background, lets now take a look at the framing of argument from the article.</p>

<h2 id="anarchy">Anarchy</h2>

<p>The Judge writes</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The citizens of this country have great faith in the judiciary. Such strident attacks may erode that faith. If this happens, our country would cease to be governed by the rule of law and only anarchy and tyranny will reign. …</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I cant tell if these statements are borne out of ignorance (or) delusion (or) class solidarity with his [ruling] class (or) its a claptrap.</p>

<p>This man is an insider, recently retired as a Judge from Supreme Court of India. Why is he trying to appropriate the agency of avg person, cloak himself as a member of “citizens” grouping &amp; make claims on behalf of this mythical “citizen” he has invented in his head? Shall we also allow all other members of ruling class of this country (Modi, Adani, Ambani, Arvind Kejriwal, Rahul Gandhi, …) to make claims in similar manner “having great faith” about their own illegitimate power? Is he doing this to artificially boost credibility for members of his own class — buddy Judges in Supreme Court? He is not a poor man, not even an average person on the street, definitely not a powerless person (Clue: Powerless people won’t be allowed to write their opinion in Indian mainstream media owned by Capitalists). Despite retiring, he is still a member of the ruling class of India as he can still peddle influence through his connections.</p>

<p>There is a saying that goes something like: <em>fool me once, shame on you; fool me twice, shame on me</em>. Given what we know about the history of Indian Supreme Court &amp; its appointments (self-dealing &amp; collusion with all forces of hegemony — Executive, Capital, Majoritarianism, Casteism, Misogyny, …), who are these people that have “great faith” in our so-called “Supreme” &amp; “Justices”<sup id="fnref:judge-as-justice"><a href="#fn:judge-as-justice" class="footnote">3</a></sup>? Why are Indians gaslit by their ruling class/its agents that they must have irrational &amp; religious faith in these institutions that lords over them with no accountability? Is it because victims of Indian ruling class (includes Judiciary) don’t have a choice in the matter except accepting proclamations from “Justices” — however anti-factual &amp; irrational these proclamations might be?</p>

<p>Apparently, “rule of law” i.e. imposition of laws [that most of us never consented to voluntarily] is somehow good — even if the laws are bad &amp; actively harmful (which many Indian laws are). Why?</p>

<p>Anarchy is the absence of Tyranny.</p>

<p>Is the author using a different definition of Anarchy i.e. <em>chaos</em>, which is what all other political structures (including current one we are coerced to live under in India) that are built around domination/tyranny create? Anarchism does have order, but it’s not the kind of order that’s enforced through domination/tyranny (which is what State is all about), rather it’s the order achieved through non-dominating means i.e. voluntary cooperation backed by autonomy &amp; self-defence.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Definition</p>

  <p>Anarchism: The political theory that a community is best organized by the voluntary cooperation of individuals, rather than by a government, which is regarded as being coercive by nature.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In essence, Anarchy — the philosophy behind Anarchism — is the ultimate goal of a mature society, where everyone will be able to fulfill one’s potential, to live life how one wishes to live through voluntary cooperation without being dominated by another individual/group. This requires ensuring no one accumulates disproportionate power (political/economical/weaponry/…) to threaten the well-being of anyone else.</p>

<p>State is the negation of Anarchy. State is an agent of chaos &amp; injustice. Its enforces its injustice through violence as it centralises most power through a rigid hierarchy &amp; wields this power to serve interests of ruling class (those who have access to this power) — while terrorising the people it imposes itself over.</p>

<p>In essence, the Judge is using the definition of State (a tyrant &amp; a chaos agent) to blame Anarchy. In his confusion about words, he is threatening people with better society, one of Anarchy — a society without a government, a society without domination. When existing system is behaving exactly how its designed, he goes on to blame something other than the system he personally benefited — and still benefits — from. Most likely, he might not even know various political ideologies (understandable since the qualifications required to get promoted to Indian Supreme Court requires more of lobbying talent than wider understanding of society &amp; power), which explains why he used those words. Since Indian mainstream media including newspapers are essentially propaganda agents for rich &amp; powerful, this explains why they publish these narratives that makes  ̶n̶o̶ ̶s̶e̶n̶s̶e̶ anti sense.</p>

<h2 id="self-certification">Self-certification</h2>

<p>Let’s take look at another statement of him.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I agree that the <em>collegium system</em> must be more transparent. In the recent past, the proceedings of the <em>collegium</em> have been put in the public domain. There is a greater transparency now. …</p>
</blockquote>

<p>We still have no idea why any decision is made the way its made in <em>collegium system</em><sup id="fnref:collegium-system"><a href="#fn:collegium-system" class="footnote">4</a></sup>, but still Judiciary gives itself self-certificates about “greater transparency”. Everyone knows the essential element needed to move higher in the food chain within Indian Judiciary is lobbying of politicians &amp; Judges i.e influence peddling. I personally heard stories (from trusted lawyers) that there is a pay-for-appointment scheme (only for some Judge positions, not for all Judge positions), atleast in one High Court I am aware of i.e open corruption.</p>

<p>Since Indian Judiciary has weaponized <em>Contempt of Court</em> power to attack whistleblowers, silence critics &amp; shield itself from accountability, what’s the basis for these claims about alleged transparency (self-certification) from Indian Judiciary — let alone “greater transparency”?</p>

<h2 id="concern-trolling">Concern trolling</h2>

<p>Then he concern trolls like this.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>India has one of the lowest judge-to-population ratios. In most countries, the ratio is about 50 judges per million population. We have a sanctioned strength ratio of nearly 20 per million, but the actual ratio is about 15 per million. Appointing judges is not enough. The infrastructure of the district judiciary is abysmal, to say the least. The judiciary has no control over funds and if the government does not provide funds, infrastructure cannot be improved. … Judges also work before and after their regular court hours and on weekends, reading files, preparing and dictating judgments, besides performing administrative duties. These working days are not taken into consideration.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is the same nonsense as Modi claiming (bullshitting) he is working 18hrs day — evidently in his case — to sell society to his rich buddies, collect his commission/bribes &amp; destroy whatever is left.</p>

<p>Who asked these Judges to work over weekends (or) long hours?</p>

<p>When it served Indian Judiciary interests, it invented brand-new powers of self-appointment (<em>collegium system</em>) by “interpreting” Constitution, invented Public Interest Litigation (PIL) jurisdiction out of whole cloth. PIL is the most illegitimate jurisdiction Indian Judiciary has invented using which it can pick up any issue &amp; non-issue by removing standing requirement (<em>locus standi</em>), pass any judgment on issues not before it, adjudicate on matters without petitioners, adjudicate on matters without giving notice to affected parties, refused to allow affected parties to join the dispute as an interested party, deliver orders &amp; judgments that doesn’t pass smell test, accountable to nobody however grave the harm they cause — all done at the whims of judges with no constraints.</p>

<p>None of these powers are mentioned/implied in “Constitution”. Judges invented &amp; gave themselves these powers even after these self-appointment powers were deliberately denied in Constitutional debates &amp; Constitution.</p>

<p>Indian Judiciary goes far beyond Constitution when it comes to feathering its own nest, but for some reason it cant pass a simple judgment that says — all reasonable funds needed for fulfilling all judicial functions (infrastructure, salaries, …) considering 50 judges/million population, must be automatically added to budget. Why cant Judiciary declare that deprival of required funding amounts to violation of right to fair trial, which is a straightforward violation of Constitution? What’s the difficulty in passing such a rational judgment? Indian Supreme Court has a long &amp; proud track record of passing quite a lot of awful Judgments that served its interests &amp; interests of its powerful buddies. But when it comes to things that minimise harm to people, it pretends to be powerless. Are Judges not passing such Judgments because they don’t know the legality of such a common sense judgment? Ofcourse, they know. They didn’t pass — likely wont pass — such Judgment because Judiciary as a class (along with its powerful bed-fellows — State, Capital, …) benefit from existing system.</p>

<p>Status-quo i.e the man-made artificial scarcity of lack of Judicial infrastructure in India, always keeps the system underfunded &amp; ensures anyone who is thrown/pulled into the system suffers thoroughly &amp; totally. By being unaccountable &amp; unresponsive, this Judicial system gives “incentives” to its victims by giving them an opportunity to find someone to help them jump the queue i.e peddle influence by hiring highest paid lawyers (that have backdoor understanding with “Justices”)/”big people”, who can help move victim’s petition quicker in the system for a price/consideration i.e. enable large scale systemic corruption — moral &amp; money — through influence peddling. If you are not lucky to be rich/powerful who can pay (or) have connections (knows “big people”/knows someone who knows “big people”/have friends who know insiders, …), you suffer its malicious callousness &amp; cruelty.</p>

<p>It’s the system — both Judiciary &amp; Executive/Legislature currently benefit from — is the root of the problem &amp; they don’t want any structural changes to it. What both sides (Judiciary &amp; Executive/Legislature) want is exercise unaccountable &amp; illegitimate power they currently enjoy in existing system — in peace.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>End of the day, Judiciary at its core is a political actor wearing legal clothes as it ultimately decides what political, economic, social &amp; other rights we all have, without ever proving to us its judgements are inline with our interests — ofcourse, by “interpreting” so-called Constitution &amp; Laws. If we go by history of Indian Judiciary, it mostly “interprets” Constitution (aka tea-leaf reading) to serve its own interests &amp; interests of it allies i.e forces of hegemony — State/Executive, Capital, Majoritarianism, … by undermining liberty, autonomy, equity, … of its victims (people), while simultaneously — with a forked tongue — publicly singing praises about liberty, autonomy, equity, ….</p>

<p>Executive/Legislature is very similar. Indian State (worse than avg) — just like most other States — has monopolised all coercive tools &amp; most tools of manipulation (media, indoctrination through education, …) in order to hold us hostage. Holding us hostage helps it sell access to all of us to the highest bidder without our informed consent. It strips us of our resources (natural/intellectual/markets — labour, financial, retail, …/otherwise) i.e steals our resources, sells access to these resources to its buddies (brands this looting as so-called “investment”, “divestment” &amp; recently even more brazenly calls it “monetization pipeline”), claims our resources are its own (calls it State/Government property), hides information from us &amp; terrorises us for “our own safety”. By selling access to markets &amp; controlling the rules of <em>collective bargaining</em> i.e tilting rules in favor of its buddies aka “regulating”, it leaves all its powerless victims at the mercy of their buddies. In otherwords, it systematically undermines its victims when it comes to their autonomy &amp; economic well-being. Best part: It makes us (its victims) fund its tyranny over us.</p>

<p>The sooner we understand the game at play, the sooner we start thinking about solutions to the problems we face.</p>

<h2 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h2>
<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:masturbation-circle-jerk-bdsm">
      <p>People also call self-certification as masturbation; buddy certification as circle-jerk &amp; subordinates giving certificates to bosses as BDSM. <a href="#fnref:masturbation-circle-jerk-bdsm" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:worlds-best-constitution">
      <p>Indian Constitution mockingly called World’s Best Constitution™ is written by so-called “freedom fighters” aka agents of Indian rich — Nehru &amp; co. A good portion of this Constitution is copied from an ordinary law British wrote for its Indian subjects. With enough loopholes in Constitution to terrorise &amp; lord over everyone through “lawful” violence, threat of violence, lies, secrecy &amp; lawfare, these “freedom fighters” claimed their subjects “gave themselves” this Constitution (Preamble to Indian Constitution: WE, THE PEOPLE OF INDIA … GIVE TO OURSELVES THIS CONSTITUTION). One wonders: With a Constitution like this, who needs tyranny? With “freedom fighters” like this, who needs freedom? <a href="#fnref:worlds-best-constitution" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:judge-as-justice">
      <p>In India — like in many other countries — Judges call themselves “Justices”. They think so highly of themselves, lack self-awareness to such a degree, that they won’t mind butchering the word <em>Justice</em>. <a href="#fnref:judge-as-justice" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:collegium-system">
      <p><em>Collegium system</em> is self-appointment process invented by Judicial bureaucrats, where Judges will decide amongst themselves (self-dealing scheme) who will succeed them in courts, with no input from public or political opposition. This “process” enables Judges to send their buddy names to Executive for appointment as next “Justices” &amp; Executive in turn have to approve/reject the names for appointment. Judges can override Executive decision if they reiterate same name again, but this option is generally not exercised. Since Executive have the power to frustrate these recommendations by rejecting it outright/not making any decision on specific names in time bound manner, Executive forces a closed room deal with Judiciary. This deal usually involves Judicial bureaucrats agreeing to install some pliable Judges Executive want as “Justices” in next recommendations/promotions (or) drop some names of Judges that have proven themselves somewhat independent (or) transfer some inconvenient Judges (or) who knows what other corrupt deals both of them enter into behind closed doors. Thanks to this “process”, all these new pliable “Justices” Executive installed in Court will then decide whether Executive has violated laws or not, in all future cases involving legality of Executive’s actions. <a href="#fnref:collegium-system" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>

          ]]>
          
        </description>
        
        
        <media:content medium="image" url="https://thekalinga.in/2022/12/25/self-certification-wrong-diagnosis/anarchy-scaled.jpeg" />
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://thekalinga.in/2022/12/25/self-certification-wrong-diagnosis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thekalinga.in/2022/12/25/self-certification-wrong-diagnosis/</guid>
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
        <category>Democracy</category>
        
        <category>India</category>
        
        <category>Judiciary</category>
        
        <category>State</category>
        
        <category>Anarchism</category>
        
        <category>Anarchy</category>
        
        <category>Tyranny</category>
        
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MIRROR — Farmer union's rebuttal of Indian Govt lies</title>
        <description>
          
          
          <![CDATA[
            <img src="https://thekalinga.in/2020/12/21/aikms-rebuting-lies-of-indian-govt/farmers-hen.png" alt="MIRROR — Farmer union's rebuttal of Indian Govt lies" >
            <p><img src="farmers-hen.png" alt="MIRROR — Farmer union's rebuttal of Indian Govt lies" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> <em>This is a mirror of reply published by farmer’s union to counter the deliberate lies of Indian Govt led by Narendra Modi. I took the liberty of re-posting this in accessible manner. Link to the original document is available at the end of the article.</em></p>

<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>Indian Govt. led by BJP recently passed 3 farm laws that affect millions of farmers with no consultation from farmers (or) thier unions.
The goal of these laws is to destroy the protections most Indian farmers previously had &amp; to pave way for corporate takeover of Indian farming market — further impoverishing already distressed farmers, increasing the prices for the end consumer &amp; transferring all these profits into the pockets of those that fund Modi &amp; his party.
In other words, Modi sold Indian farmers to his pay masters in exchange for keeping him in power.
Indian Govt. passed these unconstitutional laws (Agriculture is a state subject &amp; Central Govt has no role in it) in an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Uiquk0N1mU">illegal &amp; undemocratic manner</a>.</p>

<p>Farmers are protesting across the country demanding the repeal of these laws that destory thier livelihoods while enriching Capitalists (both crony &amp; non-crony).
Now Indian Govt started a massive lying campaign thru mainstream media &amp; social media to sabotage farmers protests &amp; lie to rest of the society who dont have full context as to why farmers are opposing these laws.</p>

<p>What follows is the response of a farmer’s union — All India Kisan Mazdoor Sabha (AIKMS) — to the well-calibrated lies of Indian Govt led by Narendra Modi.</p>

<h2 id="farmer-unions-view-of-govt-lies">Farmer union’s view of Govt lies</h2>

<p>Govt’s arguments for not accepting peasant demands of repealing three farm acts &amp; electricity bill (EB) 2020 are deceptive and untruthful. Its claim of having addressed specific problems in the acts are bogus. It is propagating falsehood to claim that the laws help peasants (farmers).</p>

<p><strong>Farmer’s demand</strong>: Repeal the three Farm Acts &amp; Electricity Bill 2020</p>

<h2 id="farmer-unions-detailed-response-to-govt-lies">Farmer union’s detailed response to Govt lies</h2>

<p>Since, June 2020, the peasantry of India has been agitating for repeal of the 3 New Farm Ordinances, passed into Acts in September, and the EB 2020. Despite massive mobilizations in several states and now the indefinite dharna by several lac peasants at the borders of Delhi, the Govt, through its ministers and experts and BJP leaders are continuously trying to belittle the peasant problems, giving out arguments based on wrong facts, complete misreading of the 3 acts and deliberately ignoring reference to the clauses being objected to. Their arguments are diversionary and pretentious and their claim that specific aspects have been addressed is bogus. TheGovt, as is its character,has also issued an online publicity document “Putting Farmers First”, to show how much Modi Govt has done for peasants. It is aimed at misguiding the country. We attempt here to put the facts straight.</p>

<p>We wish to inform, that the Delhi sit in has been preceded by strong mass protests in Punjab and all India protests on August 9, September 25, October 14, November 5 and others, all of which were ignored. Even Punjab govt tried to suppress the movement with arrests,but had to retreat as inthe present uprising all sections of people of Punjab. Agriculture continues to constitute an important aspect of the economic life of not only the land owning small, middle and rich peasants, but also affects large number of traders, small industry, workers, intellectuals, professionals.They feel that these laws will destroy the agricultural economic landscape of the country by handing over controls to the Big Indian and Foreign Corporate.</p>

<p>While it is being argued by pro Corporate lobbyists that this movement is only of rich farmers, it is motivated by unscrupulous Arhatiyas, it is sponsored by foreign funds and foreign powers, it is organized by opposition parties, is all wrong propaganda. The middle, small and marginal peasants constitute the main force of the agitation.</p>

<h3 id="point-by-point-rebuttal">Point by point rebuttal</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> The govt. reforms are aimed at increasing private capital,infrastructure anddevelopment to reach villages and farms and that will benefit peasants. Govt. has allotted ₹1 lac crore for helping private investment in ware-housing and other infra structure. This will make villages Atmnirbhar.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The two acts — Farmers’ Produce Trade and Commerce(FPTC) &amp; Contract Act clearly state that their aim is to promote private traders, corporate to establish private mandis and engage peasants in contracts. Now Corporate houses will have legal right to do so.</p>

<p>The Laws say that the govt. will promote private companies. Automatically the functioning of govt. mandis, supply of fertilizers, seeds, electricity, irrigation will be get de-promoted. Existing Govt sector is easily bribed into dysfunction in order to serve private and corporate interests. This has happened to Public Sector Industries, Airlines, Insurance, Telecom Services, Healthcare, Schools, Clean water supply and other civic facilities and is now happening in Electricity supply, Railways, Banking, etc. Govt welfare schemes are being largely undermined under the guise of handing over to Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR), whose performance is zero, but is never questioned. Wherever corporate has entered any service, govt sector suffers further losses, while the corporates make huge profits.</p>

<p>In all sectors, once govt facility becomes sick and non-functional, its assets are sold to the Corporates. This will happen to agriculture infrastructure also, viz the mandis, the irrigation facilities and FCI warehouses, amongst others. For last 20 years there have been attempts to privatize irrigation via Self Help Groups. Water from big Dams built for irrigation is being supplied to industry and cities. FCI suffers a loan of more than ₹3 lac crores, because over last 8 years its expenses have not been recleared by the govt from the food subsidy budget. All its assets will get sold.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Peasantry itself had asked for reforms. Now why oppose the laws?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The peasants had demanded improvement in mandi functioning, not ‘mukti’ from mandis. Now these mandis will perish.</p>

<p>Peasants have clearly stated they are opposed to any direct and further penetration corporate, MNCs, International Grain Traders in agriculture because they will raise input costs, depress crop rates, which will be decided through e-NAM and not the Govt. declared MSP (Section 5b of Contract Act) and will control the entire food chain. This will lead to higher cost of farming, higher losses, higher debts and displacement from land. Peasants will be ruined.</p>

<p>The new acts will legalise entry of Corporate and allow them to control farming process, input supplies, marketing of crops, food storage, food processing, processed food industry, etc. This will make all aspects village life Corporate Nirbhar.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> We improved mandis. Farmers are being made a ‘market force’.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The actual improvements claimed in Mandis are only computerization and e-NAMs, which hardly bring any meaningful benefit to common peasants. The reforms sought by peasants in Mandis werefor better storage, transport, infrastructure, procurement assurance for all crops at MSP, end to corruption, more democratic functioning of Mandi Samitis, better institutional low interest credit facilities to save them from private credit of Arhatiyas, etc.</p>

<p>Govt claim of making farmers a market force cannot benefit the peasants if they are exposed to big traders and corporates. They will only become victims of corporate loot. Freedom of choice between a goat and a tiger is only for the tiger. APMC mandis were legally set up to protect them from big traders, who depress crop prices, knowing that the farmer cannot retain his crop and it is his compulsion to sell, as he has debts to clear and has to buy inputs for the next sowing. It was also to prevent excessive difference between farm and retail prices, as big traders tend to hoard and do black marketing.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Private mandis are only an alternative and there is no compulsion to sell over there. Farmers have the option to sell their crop anywhere now. He can take his crop to any state and sell it. Laws provide freedom of choice.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Private mandis will become the only option with a vast network of middlemen in all villages. Peasant never dictate prices, as their only option is the nearest available mandi and the available buyers there. They cannot bear the burden of transporting their crop to another mandi. Can sell anywhere is being stated only to fool those who may not be aware of the problems of farming, particularly those of urban middle class.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> We brought parity between APMC and private mandis by proposing to allow state govts to tax private mandis, register all purchasers and contracts.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>These are Central Act give legal freedom to big corporate to control all aspects on agriculture. As per the govt’s latest proposal, the onus of even minor checks on these companies will be fulfilled by the state govts, who will decide, depending on which parties are ruling. If all powers to check are with the state, then why is there a Central Act? Obviously, the role of Central Govt. and Central Acts is to promote corporate and MNC’s in agriculture, which can easily undo the checks by state as per need. Once companies gain access, it will be very difficult for the next govt. to undo it them.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> In several states, like Bihar, there were no APMS mandis, there the farmers have no problem.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Bihar and several states have had no APMC mandis. But no state has given license to corporates to establish their private mandis, which is the main problem with these Acts. Because Punjab has APMC, farmers there got the MSP rate of ₹1868 per quintal. In most of UP and Bihar it is selling at ₹900 to ₹1200 per quintal to traders. They then sell it to big buyers and corporate. When Corporate Mandis will get established in all states, these prices will be depressed further.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> During Modi’s rule in Gujarat it transformed lives of farmers.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>During Modi period Narmada Dam water, which was meant to irrigate agricultural land, was largely diverted for industry and Sabarmati River Water Front. Every year farmers hold big protests for water supply which is cut off before the crops are ready.</p>

<p>The real picture of Gujarat’s Modi Model is revealed by several facts including the case of Missing Farmers in 2011 NSSO report which revealed that between 2001–2011 3.55 lac farmers had gone missing in Gujarat and there was a massive rise of 17 lac agricultural labour. Studies report that this landlessness increased due to promotion of export driven corporate farming. And worker wages were amongst the lowest in Gujarat, with urban labour getting ₹144 against a national average of ₹170 and of rural labour from ₹113 against a national average of ₹139. Female labour were paid only ₹69 per day.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Farmers will not lose his land. Section 15 on Contract Act clearly states that farmer will not lose land. The law can be strengthened.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The contract with the sponsor company does not include mortgaging of peasant’s land. But Sec. 9 of Contract Act provides for peasants to take loans from other ‘debt instruments’, as separate and parallel deals. For making payment to the sponsor company for the inputs provided by it to the peasant he will have to take loans and his land will be mortgaged.</p>

<p>Section 14(2)(b) of Contract Act provides that where the “order is against the farmer for recovery of the amount due to the Sponsor”, which may be on account of “any advance payment or cost of inputs”, “such amount shall not exceed the actual cost incurred by the Sponsor”. So, apart from cost of inputs or advance, the actual costs ‘incurred by the Sponsor’ will be recovered from the farmer! All recoveries will be made of arrears and land revenue as per Sec. 14(7) of this Act.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> The laws create ‘better lives for farmers and jobs for rural youth’, referring to private investments for this.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Land of the peasants can only be saved if the govt gives an unsecured loan which no private company will give. With no provision for that in the Contract Act, it is likely that a parallel structure of money lenders serving these companies, but formally independent of it, like rise of mahajans during East India Company, will develop. If the peasant cannot get an institutional loan, then the burden on him/her to pay for services provided by the company will force him to take recourse to borrowing from other sources and in the process have to part with their land. Though this will formally not be part of the Contract agreement, but in reality, it will be very much essential part of it. Linkage between companies and money lenders can be multifaceted.</p>

<p>While creating conditions of peasants losing their land and become landless, Govt. says it is ‘creating more avenues for income generation’ and private investments will generate employment. How can there be better lives when land is lost? When companies invest in rural areas, they do not create infrastructure to help farmers to earn. They take over land for real estate, industrial use, in which only handful of jobs are created while thousands lose their land and livelihood. Most land taken in the name of industries is not developed and remains idle for long.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Acts will give written assurance that MSP and Govt procurement will continue &amp; Modi govt. has already implemented Swaminathan Formula.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Modi govt. has failed to implement Swaminathan formula <em>C2 cost + 50%</em>. <em>C2 cost</em> is total cost of cultivation (including full labour cost, cost of depreciation of equipment, land rent, interest). Modi govt. itself claimed that in 2017 and 2018 the MSP declared was <em>A2 + FL + 50%</em>. For many crops the MSP declared was even less than this. <em>A2 cost</em> is payments made by the peasant and Family Labour of 8 days. Modi govt. gave an affidavit in Supreme Court that it cannot pay <em>C2 + 50%</em> because food cost will rise.</p>

<p>Peasantry’s demand is to increase MSP at <em>C2 + 50%</em> for all crops and ensure that all peasants get the MSP rate for their crops. Presently govt. declares MSP for only 23 crops, only few peasants get its benefit as implementation is only in some areas and is tardy.</p>

<p>Govt. spokespersons and experts are claiming that the country has excessive food stock, more than 2.5 times than what is required. There is no space to store food. It cannot buy so much wheat, paddy, pulses, etc. Obviously, the govt. does not want to buy and its claim of continuing MSP and procurement is a complete hoax.</p>

<p>Govt’s lie is further nailed by its own document, PFF which says ‘ensure proper prices for produce’. It does not even say — ensure MSP is given.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Acceding to demand for MSP will raise food costs.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Govt is trying to deny MSP at <em>C2 + 50%</em> in the name of keeping food costs low for the poor people. Giving <em>C2 + 50%</em> as MSP will not make food costly if input costs are decreased proportionally. This will afford savings for farmers and agriculture will become sustainable. But govt wants to allow corporate to sell costly inputs and keep the food costs lowby depriving peasants of profitable MSP. Thus, at both ends the peasant is squeezed and Corporate profit is secured. The Govt’s logic of not giving MSP is to pit workers against peasants andserve the interest of corporate. They will reap the benefit of selling inputs to peasants at high cost as well as buy cheap crops which keep both industrial inputs and wages cost low.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Farmers can fix prices for produce even before growing it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Monopsony i.e. one buyer and many sellers cannot create condition for peasant to bargain and fix prices. To say that the peasant can dictate at the time of the Contract is absurd, because the Companies always have a better idea of prices and they fix what is profitable to them. Moreover, at the time of purchase, there are many provisions for the company to deny the price fixed in the contract.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Acts will double by 2022. Input cost have been decreased.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Diesel cost has been increased tremendously by Modi govt, even though international prices crude oil have fallen $110 per barrel in 2014 to $40–50 per barrel now. Today total tax on diesel and petrol is around 50 rupees, which is about 65% of the price of fuel. Ready to sell petrol in India was ₹24.62 while diesel was ₹26.02 in May end this year. The tax includes central excise duty of ₹32.98 on petrol which was only ₹9.20 in November 2014 and ₹31.83 on diesel which was only ₹3.46 in November 2014. Fuel prices in Pakistan, Bangladesh, Srilanka are cheaper than in India. Diesel effects tilling, irrigating, harvesting and transports costs. Though there is little variation in increase in different fertilizer prices, seeds, insecticides and farm equipment are sold by companies at very high costs. It is not regulated by the govt. Every year the prices are raised and peasants have to take loans to pay for these.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Old system of APMC was brought in when there was food shortage. Now we are food surplus and we need to change and move ahead.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Food surplus is a big lie. Every year India is falling in the list of world hunger index. This year it is 94 out of 107 countries, which is even below Srilanka, Bangladesh and Pakistan. More than 68% of deaths in under five children in India are due to malnutrition (Lancet). The most recent National Family Heath Survey released two days backshows that since 2015–16 percentage of under five children who are stunted remains at 36%, showing no improvement at all. Stunting in under-fives is almost entirely due to poor nutrition and reflects status of food availability in society. There is also no improvement in Infant Mortality Rate during these 5 years, which also reflects status of nutrition and health care.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> New system is revolutionary as it does away with middlemen who exploited farmers, charged commission to raise prices. Fragmented structure of markets also led to high cost for consumers and depressed prices received by farmers.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The farmers complaint was against high interest private usurious loans. The solution was cheap inputs and cheap loans. The govt has not done that. It is tricking the people by saying middlemen’s commission charges raised food prices. The difference between what a farmer gets and what the consumer buys is at times in multiples and is mainly dueto high transport costs, illegal taxes extracted by the officials and due to hoarding and black marketing. Commission charges are only a maximum of 8.5%, which is nothing. Farmers always receive very low prices when the market is monopolized by big buyers, even when there is shortage in the market. High cost to consumers too is driven by monopoly control by companies.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> FPOs, Farmer Producer Organizations are a revolution as they empower the farmers.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Farmer Producer Organizations, FPOs were made to empower farmers, but this can happen only if they function as farmers cooperatives with govt. support. Section 10 of the Contract Acts list FPOs and Agriculture Cooperative Societies to function as “aggregator and farm service provider”. That is a middlemen orbichauliya for companies to aggregate crops; to supply inputs and services (Section 2, Contract Act); to operate private mandis; to determine “quality, grade and standards for pesticide residue, food safety standards, good farming practices and labour and social development standards” and certify the (crop assayer - Section 4 Contract Act); and Section 5 of the FPTC Act provides for FPOs, to own and operate the private mandis and to decide rules and guidelines for fair trade practices, decide mandi charges, etc. They will become middlemen of the corporate to exploit farmers, with no Govt control.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> In the Contract Act if market prices go up, farmer can sell outside the contract. If market prices fall the sponsor company will have to give the contracted rate. Central Govt’s document, PFF claims ‘contractors cannot end agreement without full payment’.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Both claims are total lies and baseless. Sections 4 and 6 of Contract Act clearly states that at the time of purchase quality and rate of crop will be assessed by a ‘assayer’ who can be notified in the contract is signed or appointed later. Obviously, companies will have a larger say in such appointment. It will be his job to assess and settle the payment to be made and will not be the ‘full payment’ as per the rate in the contract.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Buyers must pay on time of face or legal action.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This also is wrong. Section 6(3) of the Contract Act allows taking the crop by only by issuing the receipt slip, while the mode and manner of payment can be decided by the state govt. It also grants 30 days time for payments for seed production. FPTC allows buyer to delay the payment by 3 days after taking the crop and issuing a receipt. It also allows delay in payment till such time as the FPO or Agri Coop receives payment from the person he further sells the crop to. Section 4 (3) states that “Central Government may prescribe a different procedure of payment by farmer producer organization or agriculture co-operative society, by whatever name called, linked with the receipt of payment from the buyers”. We know how Sugar Mills delay payments for years.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Farmer can end agreement in any time</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This claim is a blatant lie and the law is clear. The peasant is bound by the contract terms and will be prosecuted under the Act. Moreover, when the first step in the implementation of the agreement is that the farmer pays the company for inputs, how can he end it?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> These Contracts are only an alternative and if the farmer chooses he can refuse to enter a contract.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The farmers are and will be lured into these contracts and will learn about them only when they suffer losses. Entire experience of contract farming with some commercial crops like flowers, oranges, potatoes, tomatoes, eucalyptus plantations,etc in Punjab, Gujarat, Karnataka, UP and other states has been of some initial gains to farmers. Invariably this has led to growth in contracts and invariably farmers have suffered heavily later and many have lost their land. This happened on a big scale in Punjab. In Gujarat, 9 farmers were sued for a ₹1 crore rupees, for using the FC-5 potato seed, without permission from Pepsico.</p>

<p>Secondly, the govt. has been claiming all along that these Acts are creating a new system for benefit of farmers. Question arises that while the old inadequate system which failed the farmers will perish, and the new system ‘may not be opted for by the farmer’, then what new system/ opportunity/ have these laws given the farmer?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Exports will help farmers. They will become part of value chains.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Exports will help traders and companies. Tied to Giant value chains and exporters, it is these companies who will benefit from cheap and assured purchase from the farmer who will be contracted to sell. The farmer will neither sell directly to the consumer, nor will he/she export. The companies will do that.</p>

<p>Moreover, freedom to export and import given to these companies means they will source cheapest food from international markets and refuse to buy Indian farmers’ produce, thus affecting production here and jeopardizing food production and security of the country.</p>

<p>The Govt gives slogan of <em>Atma Nirbharta of farmers will increase</em>, actually meaning there by that their dependence on the Govt support will end. Design is to make Agriculture, Agro Processing and Marketing completely Corporate Nirbhar.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> These laws will ‘see India’s agriculture and food processing industry being reformed’. ‘Private investments will pour in across entire cold chain, providing efficient and cheaper resource supply, reducing losses and ensuring better prices for farmers’.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>While it is correctly said that these laws have been made for agro processing industry to grow and for better private investments, this is precisely the fear of farmers. Although the Govt says it is to provide more opportunities to farmers, page 16 of the Govt document, PFF, confesses who these reforms are meant for ‘Just imagine the kind of new avenues that are going to open up for agri business with these reforms’. The private investor giants will invest to make profit, not to give better prices to peasants.</p>

<p>The demand of farmers and rural youth is that govt should provide for cost-based technology and inputs directly to the peasants or through the Cooperative sector. In Punjab there is a big demand that since every peasant has to own a tractor, other machinery and pumps, these should be supplied by the Govt, to bring down input costs, i.e. providing efficient and cheaper resources. If companies provide resources, they will do so at very high cost, which will ruin the farmers.</p>

<p>Rural transformation does require development of Food Processing Industry. The Farmers demand is that the govt must provide its infrastructure and structure for marketing and allow peasants to earn from food processing. Only then can it improve farmers’ income, not by asking Corporate to invest.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Removed food items from the Essential Commodities Act to make farmers benefit from high prices.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Food is the most Essential Commodity for survival. Unchecked, traders and companies indulge in unscrupulous hoarding and black marketing, raising cost of food and leading to starvation and hunger deaths. During last two decades India has witnessed large number of hunger deaths. Some facts on food insufficiency have been noted above.</p>

<p>Having removed food grains from list of Essential Commodities, hoarding, black marketing and other unfair trade practices will rise. It will benefit only agro processing companies and big traders. How PM Modi feels farmers will benefit from this immoral, anti-people change is not clear. This will harm both the farmer and the consumer and help only the Corporate and MNC food giants.</p>

<p>The changes in EC Act allow for 50% hike in annual dry food (cereals, pulses) prices and 100% hike in vegetables and fruits. This is the new written law now.</p>

<p>The EC Act also raises doubts about continuation of the Targeted PDS rules, for which it states ‘for the time being in force’. Winding up of PDS will force more than 75 crore beneficiaries to buy from open market controlled by the Corporate.</p>

<p>This logic of the Govt is again to pit farmers against workers. While Food costs will tend to rise high, farmers will not benefit as they will be bound by contracts and Corporate control over mandis.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Govt claim:</strong> Modi govt has done a lot for farmers in terms of PMKISAN, PMFBY, rural credit growth, pension schemes, loan waivers, MNREGA funds, etc.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Each scheme of the Govt has been planned only under pressure of farmers movement. Each has been saddled with large propaganda, poor performance and large scale corruption.</p>

<p>The fact is that the farmers have still become the most powerless citizens in India. They are on the streets today to save their land and retention of some old privileges in law, which are going to be undermined by these new 3 Farm Laws and EB 2020. The govt must withdraw them. Only then can there be any dialogue on what changes to make which will benefit the farmers.</p>

<p>All India Kisan Mazdoor Sabha appeals to you to come out and support the peasants in their struggle against the Corporate and MNCs.</p>

<h2 id="credit">Credit</h2>

<p><strong>Publisher:</strong></p>

<p>Central Executive Committee,
All India Kisan Mazdoor Sabha (AIKMS),
(Kirti Kisan Union, Punjab),
Member of <em>All India Kisan Sangharsh Coordination Committee (AIKSCC)</em></p>

<p><strong>Author:</strong></p>

<p>Dr. Ashish Mital, General Secretary, AIKMS</p>

<p><strong>Published on:</strong></p>

<p>19th Dec 2020</p>

<p><strong>Original:</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://thekalinga.in/assets/aikms-farmers-reply.pdf">Download</a></p>

          ]]>
          
        </description>
        
        
        <media:content medium="image" url="https://thekalinga.in/2020/12/21/aikms-rebuting-lies-of-indian-govt/farmers-hen.png" />
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://thekalinga.in/2020/12/21/aikms-rebuting-lies-of-indian-govt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thekalinga.in/2020/12/21/aikms-rebuting-lies-of-indian-govt/</guid>
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
        <category>Democracy</category>
        
        <category>Farm laws</category>
        
        <category>AIKMS</category>
        
        <category>Farmer union reply</category>
        
        <category>India</category>
        
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why fascist NRC must be fought tooth &amp; nail</title>
        <description>
          
          
          <![CDATA[
            <img src="https://thekalinga.in/2019/11/24/why-fascist-nrc-should-be-opposed/indian-farmer.jpeg" alt="Why fascist NRC must be fought tooth & nail" >
            <p><img src="indian-farmer.jpeg" alt="Why fascist NRC must be fought tooth &amp; nail" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<p><strong>ADVISORY</strong>: Article contains strong language</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it</p>

  <p>— George Santayana</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Indian Govt led by fascist BJP is planning to conduct a country wide hunt for “<a href="https://theprint.in/opinion/with-assam-nrc-the-truth-is-also-out-it-was-a-pointless-exercise-all-along/284929/">alleged</a>” illegal immigrants with the unspecified intent of punishing the poor, illiterate &amp; most importantly <a href="https://www.news18.com/news/politics/bjp-vows-to-strip-muslim-immigrants-of-vote-in-assam-1214700.html">Muslims</a>.
The primary goal is show people that they being in Govt can do whatever the hell they want to do to push the country towards <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/hegde-kicks-up-a-fresh-row-with-remarks-on-secularism/article22271584.ece?homepage=true">anti-secular</a> <a href="https://hinduexistence.org/2017/05/18/remove-secular-from-constitution-to-make-bharat-as-hindu-state-togadia/">Goonish Hindu state</a> &amp; we all can do nothing about it.
The whole exercise of <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/nrc-across-country-will-send-excluded-out-amit-shah-6008047/">National Register of Citizens (NRC)</a> is a ploy to intimidate, discriminate, punish, steal the property of Muslims &amp; the ultimate humiliation of making them stateless.</p>

<p>In this article, I’ll explain everything I said above with sufficient documentory evidence.
I will also give you reasons as to why we must fight this fascistic move tooth &amp; nail.</p>

<p><strong>TLDR:</strong>
I will boycott this fascist NRC &amp; will not submit my documents for verification. I have no reason to prove to these fascist Goons that I am an Indian. You too should do the same &amp; join street protests to oppose this. If enough of us boycott it, there is nothing they can do about it.</p>

<p>Here are the list of reasons (each point explained later in detail)</p>

<ol>
  <li>Its plain unjust</li>
  <li>Its based on a proven lie</li>
  <li>Its a fascist wedge to humiliate Muslims, take over their property &amp; make them stateless</li>
  <li>Needless misery of the most vulnerable</li>
  <li>NRC = Demonetisation 2.0</li>
  <li>Ploy to distract from every other important issue</li>
  <li>Cost of implementation</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>Congress, AAP &amp; most of Indian opposition parties have self castrated themselves long back &amp; have no fighting spirit in them.
They are in no mood to fight for their own turf, let alone fighting for you (or) for me (or) for our Muslim brothers and sisters (or) any just cause for that matter.
These opportunistic cowards even <a href="https://www.telegraphindia.com/india/aap-hails-scrapping-of-article-370-supports-bill-on-bifurcation-of-j-k/cid/1695887">praised</a> the illegal annexation of Kashmir in an unconstitutional manner by Goons sitting in Delhi.
They supported it despite knowing it to be immoral &amp; unconstitutional while also knowing the whole annexation happened under the pretence of a <a href="https://thewire.in/politics/bjp-kashmir-terrorist-threat-lie-article-370">lie</a>, thru <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-49481180">military terror</a>, in the hopes that thru brute state terror legitimate aspirations of millions of Kashmiris can be suppressed.</p>

<p>Indian Courts are fully compromised &amp; these unaccountable black gowns of Supreme Court are the ones who imposed this cruel NRC on Assam &amp; sat idle for more than 100 days while the <a href="https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/kashmir-internet-shutdown-for-over-100-days-a-violation-of-right-to-life-submits-dushyant-dave-149949">fundamental rights of Kashmiries are violated</a> thru military terror.</p>

<p>There is nothing we can expect from the cowardly, corrupt &amp; opportunistic opposition (or) the so-called “courts” of this country.
Injustice is <em>not</em> the exception in our country, its the rule &amp; its unleashed thru various state organs in cohorts with Indian courts.</p>

<p>Both opposition &amp; courts are nothing more than power brokers who are interested in their own power &amp; none of the responsibilities that come with it.
They are passive collaborators in the sinister majoritarian Hindutva anti-secular game played by the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2018/world/reports-of-hate-crime-cases-have-spiked-in-india/">thugs of BJP</a>.
Anytime a serious issue of principle is involved, this joke of an opposition immediately runs into hiding/side with injustice.
This is what enabled the thugs of BJP to abuse the system this openly &amp; brazenly.
These opposition parties seek vote in the name of Secularism by scaring everyone that the Goon (BJP) is really awful. But instead of protesting on street &amp; forcing these fascists to backdown, all they do is Drama sitting in this air-conditioned houses—while thier agents in media do thier bidding (promoting them).
We have seen this Good Cop, Bad Cop nonsense for long enough from opposition.</p>

<p>[Despite his own flaws] Gandhi organised protests to fight foreign invaders thru non-violence &amp; non-cooperation.
Its not that hard to fight these domestic fascist bullies who are children of Godse (Gandhi’s killer). 
If enough of us hit streets in protests &amp; tell them that we will boycott this domestic fascist move of NRC, there is nothing they can do about it.
The more you let a bully win, the more pain he inflicts on everyone around him.
Our compliance &amp; silence emboldens the bully.
Lets disabuse ourselves for once by telling the bully that he can only bully us when we are divided, not when we are united.</p>

<p>Prime Goon<sup id="fnref:prime-goon"><a href="#fn:prime-goon" class="footnote">1</a></sup> aka <a href="https://www.modilies.in/">Conman</a> aka Modi is a <a href="https://thewire.in/media/narendra-modi-press-conference">Coward</a>.
He cant even take an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NbOQa8p080A">unscripted question</a> &amp; needs to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G3PKuc9Nsb4">drink water</a> when anyone asks an unscripted question.
I have no doubt he will cry like a baby if any journalist who is worth his salt confronts him on his criminal track record in Gujrat. 
Just like his Guru Savarkar who wrote <a href="https://thewire.in/history/bhagat-singh-and-savarkar-a-tale-of-two-petitions">apology letters to British begging them to release him from prison during freedom struggle</a>, these bullies are the most cowardly bunch you will ever encounter.
The more we sit silent, the more they do whatever the hell they want to do.</p>

<p>We need to hit the streets &amp; oppose these fascist snakes that spew venomous communal poison on day to day basis, which are born in that snake pit RSS.</p>

<p>Here are the reasons why we all should oppose NRC, both online &amp; offline. Most importantly offline, by hitting the streets in protests.</p>

<h2 id="1-its-plain-unjust">1. Its plain unjust</h2>

<p>Jurisprudence is found on the basic principle that everyone is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presumption_of_innocence">innocent until proven guilty</a>.
In case of NRC, everyone is guilty until proven innocent.
This is the reversal of the role of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burden_of_proof_(law)">burden of proof</a>.
Instead of Govt proving someone is guilty, we all have to prove we are innocent of the crimes we did not commit.
This is the law of despots who dont care for the suffering they inflict on others.
Its the opposite of justice.</p>

<p>Why should a whole country needs to prove they are not criminals?
This is an unreasonable &amp; cruel standard &amp; <a href="https://www.telegraphindia.com/india/everything-you-want-to-know-about-the-nrc/cid/1352646">Supreme Court of India was the enabler</a> of this cruelty.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If a rape happens in a city, you dont ask all male members to come and prove they are not the rapists, rather Govt has the burden to go, find and ultimately prove who the actual guilty party is—with evidence—in the court of law.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Only in fascist kafkaesque unjust societies do everyone needs to prove that they not guilty of the crimes they did not commit</p>

<h2 id="2-its-based-on-a-proven-lie">2. Its based on a proven lie</h2>

<p>BJP &amp; the poisonous tree from which its born, RSS have insisted Assam is overflowing with illegal <a href="https://www.economist.com/leaders/2019/07/11/indias-hunt-for-illegal-immigrants-is-aimed-at-muslims">Bangladeshi Muslim immigrants</a>.
Now, that Assam NRC is over, it has come about that the <a href="https://thewire.in/government/hindus-muslims-forged-documents-nrc">number of Hindus who forged documents is much higher than Muslims</a>.
The whole lie of BJP fell on its face.</p>

<p>When their lie is fully exposed, sore losers of BJP wants to impose one more round of NRC on Assamese &amp; also want all of us to prove that we are not illegals.
Why should we?
These fascists lied that there were <a href="https://www.outlookindia.com/magazine/story/india-news-even-hindus-are-illegal-immigrants-in-assams-ambitious-national-register-of-citizens-bjp-on-backfoot/302099">crores of illegal immigrants</a>.
Now its a proven lie.</p>

<p>Most of these people who are not yet in the register are yet to exhaust all their legal options.
Many of these people are not yet in the system because our system is so flawed.
Many of these people are still Indians because very few people prior to 1980s have documentary evidence as we are not documentation based society historically, especially in villages.</p>

<h2 id="3-its-a-fascist-wedge-to-humiliate-muslims-take-over-their-property--make-them-stateless">3. Its a fascist wedge to humiliate Muslims, take over their property &amp; make them stateless</h2>

<p>Soon after becoming Chancellor, Hitler passed <a href="https://encyclopedia.ushmm.org/content/en/article/anti-jewish-legislation-in-prewar-germany">citizen laws</a> that every German needs to prove they are “real” Germans thru blood &amp; ancestry.
All those who could not prove they are Germans with documentary evidence and/or blood lines were declared illegals.
They were subjected to violence, humiliation, sent to concentration camps, made stateless, their properties taken over by fascist Germans &amp; millions of jews finally paid the ultimate price with life.</p>

<p>The poisonous snakes of RSS who spout the <a href="https://sabrangindia.in/article/hate-watch-bjp-mla-raja-singh-officially-repeat-offender-hate-speech">most venomous communal poison</a> on day to day basis are founded by those who consider <a href="https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/news/national/golwalkar-drew-lessons-from-hitlers-germany/article7924161.ece">Hitler to be a great man</a> &amp; <a href="https://thewire.in/world/german-ambassador-walter-lindner-rss-headquarters">Nazism to be a great philosophy</a>.
These goons now want to do the same with Muslims &amp; other minorities.
Its immoral to sit idle while these fascists impose this level of cruelty on our fellow citizens.</p>

<h2 id="4-needless-misery-of-the-most-vulnerable">4. Needless misery of the most vulnerable</h2>

<p>No good reason is provided to prove that India is overwhelmed with illegal immigrants &amp; all evidence point in the opposite direction, i.e spite to punish Muslims.
I am from a village background &amp; my village is not in a remote place in India.
Even then when I went to pursue my master of engineering degree (out of state, which I dropped out of), I never had any documentation—other than my education certificates—as evidence of my existence (not even voter id as I dint apply for one back then).</p>

<p>If a person like me who atleast has some level of education had nothing much to show for other than my education certificates (&amp; my parent’s documentation assuming thier name is spelled correctly &amp; there is no translation mismatch between thier names in my mother tongue &amp; English in older documents) to prove my existence, because of this fascist NRC, we somehow have to pretend all poor &amp; illiterate have documentary evidence dating as far back as 1980s, i.e ~40years back to prove they were here in India before that?
For what? To satisfy a small group of Hindu fascists who lied &amp; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2002_Gujarat_riots">murdered thier way</a> to the top political position in the country &amp; want to use NRC as a wedge to further their bigotry &amp; state sponsored cruelty?</p>

<p>Most rich people will have documentation for quite a long time because they had land &amp; so held decent amount of documentation, but what about all those vulnerable people who live in slums without much documentation?
A large % of people in cities will have documentation when compared to villagers because villages operate on the principle of trust, does not require &amp; does not use as much documentation. You will find a farmer rarely selling his produce with paper trail.</p>

<p>This whole NRC exercise is a ploy to punish poor, minorities, illiterate, slum dwellers, villagers, landless peasants, Dalits, vagabonds, beggars, people who ran away from house, abandoned kids &amp; more.
This exercise will inflict needless misery on everyone, especially the poorest &amp; the most vulnerable (minorities) amongst us.</p>

<h2 id="5-nrc--demonetisation-20">5. NRC = Demonetisation 2.0</h2>

<p>The naked emperor’s Tughlaq decision of <a href="https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2016/12/03/the-dire-consequences-of-indias-demonetisation-initiative">Demonetisation</a> has <a href="https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2017/01/07/the-high-economic-costs-of-indias-demonetisation">destroyed the whole economy</a>.
Neo Tughlaq even went so far as to <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/opinion/op-ed/a-politically-inconvenient-data-nugget/article29214638.ece">suppress this data</a>.
We are currently on our way to <a href="https://www.cgdev.org/blog/if-india-stopped-growing-would-imf-and-world-bank-say-so">economic depression</a>.
This Neo Tughlaq has no right to impose one more Tughlaqi decision &amp; unleash this level of cruelty on us all once again—let alone on larger scale &amp; one that has severe consequences.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Demonetization 1.0 destroyed economic fabric of this country, Demonetization 2.0 (NRC) will destroy the social fabric of this country &amp; instill state terror into everyone’s heart.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>These Goons are doing everything they can to destroy the social fabric by inciting communal violence in UP, Rajastan &amp; everywhere they rule.</p>

<p>NRC is a ploy to tell all of us that the Servant (Govt) is stronger than the Master (Citizen) &amp; the master should be terrified of the servant.
We should never let that happen.
Hundreds died <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/timworstall/2016/12/08/indias-demonetisation-kills-100-people-apparently-this-is-not-an-important-number/">needless death</a> standing in queues when the terror of Demonetization 1.0 was unleashed.
Many committed <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/man-declared-foreigner-dies-in-assam-family-refuses-to-accept-body-2116629">suicide in Assam</a> because of NRC.</p>

<p>Why should we as citizens pay the ultimate price for the fascistic fantasises of Modern Tughlaq who is holding PM seat?</p>

<h2 id="6-ploy-to-distract-from-every-other-important-issue">6. Ploy to distract from every other important issue</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shock_and_awe">Shock &amp; Awe</a> is the tactic of fascists.
They unleash unimaginable pain on people (Shock) &amp; while we are surprised (Awe) &amp; struggle to recover from that shock, they unleash another cruel shock.
Illegal Kashmir annexation &amp; the subsequent <a href="https://www.spiegel.de/international/world/deathly-silence-an-inside-look-at-kashmir-a-1296450-amp.html">unaccountable military terror</a> (Shock) &amp; while people are shocked (Awe) and struggle to get justice on that front, these goons are planning to push one more cruel thing onto rest of the country.</p>

<p>When we are completely distracted with needless but life changing cruel acts, we will stop worrying about real important things &amp; start worrying about these madeup crises.</p>

<p>Lakhs of crores of our money in Banks is looted &amp; Prime Goon forgave all these crooks by <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/bad-loan-financial-year-rti-rbi-bank-loan-raghuram-rajan-bad-loan-financial-year-rti-rbi-bank-loan-raghuram-rajan-1140000000000-bad-debts-the-great-govt-bank-write-off/">writing off</a> all the amount without any serious implications to those who screwed us.
The <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/business/story/india-unemployment-rate-6-1-per-cent-45-year-high-nsso-report-1539580-2019-05-31">unemployment is unprecedented</a>.
The <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/maharashtra-farmer-suicide-1553467-2019-06-21">farmer’s lives</a> are miserable.</p>

<p>Now, <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/bpcl-employees-to-protest-privatisation/article29685122.ece">profit making Govt. companies like BPCL</a> will be sold to his friends Ambani/Adani.
Why should profit making public companies be sold?
Do Ambani needs to build one <a href="https://www.deccanherald.com/content/108813/soaring-above-poverty-ambanis-27.html">more vulgar billion dollar house</a> that he earned by rigging rules in his favor &amp; loot public—instead of public basic needs be taken care of?
When our schools are so bad, when our roads are awful, when people go bankrupt if they have any serious illness because of hospital costs, when Govt have no money to build new hospitals, whats the need to give our money to Ambani/Adani &amp; make these grifters even more richer by selling them BPCL?</p>

<p>When we are distracted with this needless misery of NRC, the fascists who currently rule us can complete the transformation this country into a fascist shit hole.
When we are distracted with deliberate cruelty like this, we stop paying attention to the fact that we are being fucked from behind by these fascists &amp; thier grifting friends.</p>

<p>That’s the real game plan.</p>

<h2 id="7-cost-of-implementation">7. Cost of implementation</h2>

<p>Assam is a smaller state &amp; there in order to conduct this moronic exercise of NRC, more than <a href="https://nagalandtoday.in/editorial/2019/11/people-left-out-of-nrc-in-assam-spent-rs-7836-crore-for-hearings-rights-body-survey/">~₹8,000 crores (~₹1,100 crores Govt + rest by people) was spent</a>, 65,000 workers were deployed &amp; the whole state of Assam were forced to travel, collect documentation &amp; forced to go thru miserable avoidable suffering.
What about the lost productivity of all those who have to travel, wait in lines to prove they are not illegals?
Many of the people who were deployed to verify these documents are teachers, yes, <a href="https://twitter.com/RuhulAlam72/status/1197808864583802880">teachers were asked to verify documents</a> instead of teaching kids.</p>

<p>Now the Goons sitting in Delhi wants to conduct <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/assam-bjp-unhappy-with-final-nrc-list-demands-nationwide-citizens-list/articleshow/70925109.cms">one more round of NRC in Assam</a> along with rest of India.
What about all that ₹8,000 crores that Govt + people just spent in Assam?
Who cares?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When they lose a game, the goal of fascists is forcing a rematch until they win, no matter the consequences to rest of the society.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Assam is a small state with a population of <a href="https://indiapopulation2019.com/population-of-assam-2019.html">~35 million people</a> &amp; they spent roughly ₹8,000 crores in aggregate.
How many crores will we need to spend on this cruel, unnecessary &amp; immoral exercise across a country with a population of <a href="https://indiapopulation2019.com/">~1353 million</a>?</p>

<p>(1353÷35) × ₹8,000 crores = ~₹3 lakh crores?</p>

<p>What about lost productivity because everyone now have to perform a useless task of proving they are Indian citizens?</p>

<p>For what?
So that Modern Tughlaq and his fascist regime can use us as pawn to satisfy their fascistic thirst &amp; use the consequences of the resultant fire they started as political currency in destroying Democracy?</p>

<p>Can we even begin to put a number on the misery of everyone who has to suffer thru this?</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Time for laughing at jokes aimed at these cowardly, cruel, criminal, fascistic &amp; poisonous fools of RSS &amp; BJP is over.
If we laugh at them even now, the joke is on us for letting Neo Tughlaq implement this fascist NRC.
Lets <del>follow Gandhi’s footsteps &amp;</del><sup id="fnref:gandhi-flaws"><a href="#fn:gandhi-flaws" class="footnote">2</a></sup> hit the streets to protest these fascist cowards.</p>

<p>If you have any suggestion/comment/criticism, feel free to post it in the comments.</p>

<p>NOTE: This article went thru multiple revisions as my own understanding improved over the course of time.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:prime-goon">
      <p>See <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200831070604/https://sankarshanthakur.com/2012/12/02/who-killed-haren-pandya/">Who Killed Haren Pandya?</a> on why the man who holds the position of Prime minister is a goon. Also <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/30244505-gujarat-files">Gujrat Files</a>. <a href="#fnref:prime-goon" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:gandhi-flaws">
      <p>The more I learnt about Gandhi, the more I realised the flaws of this man, such as rewriting of his own history in South Africa during his life time, well calculated deception when it comes to supporting the rotten caste system, taking huge sums of money from his corporate friends who exploited workers &amp; sabotaged worker unions from within, narcicissm to let his sycopants to refer to him as “Mahatma” (Great soul) while he was still alive. So, I dont think we need to follow flawed people. Rather its better to stick with the priciple of justice rather than idealising men, flawed or not. Read <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8521879-annihilation-of-caste">Annihilation of Caste</a> by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/B._R._Ambedkar">B.R. Ambedkar</a> if you want to understand Gandhi &amp; his duplicity. <a href="#fnref:gandhi-flaws" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>

          ]]>
          
        </description>
        
        
        <media:content medium="image" url="https://thekalinga.in/2019/11/24/why-fascist-nrc-should-be-opposed/indian-farmer.jpeg" />
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://thekalinga.in/2019/11/24/why-fascist-nrc-should-be-opposed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thekalinga.in/2019/11/24/why-fascist-nrc-should-be-opposed/</guid>
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
        <category>Democracy</category>
        
        <category>NRC</category>
        
        <category>India</category>
        
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Manufacturing Consent — How Democratic operatives are undermining Bernie Sanders 2020 candidacy</title>
        <description>
          
          
          <![CDATA[
            <img src="https://thekalinga.in/2019/09/20/manufatucturing-consent/voted.jpeg" alt="Manufacturing Consent — How Democratic operatives are undermining Bernie Sanders 2020 candidacy" >
            <p><img src="voted.jpeg" alt="Manufacturing Consent — How Democratic operatives are undermining Bernie Sanders 2020 candidacy" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If voting could change anything it would be made illegal!</p>

  <p>— Robert S. Borden</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Manufacturing consent</em> has been the modern means by which the <em>few powerful</em> gets to control the <em>many powerless</em>.
Since <em>the many</em> won’t give up their power so easily, the powerful must find new ways of convincing <em>the many</em> —
that the candidate of their choice does not enjoy popular support — so they must pick a more <em>reasonable choice</em>
to rule over them.</p>

<p>In this article, I will attempt to convince you with publicly available data that
Democratic party insiders are trying manufacture consent in the current 2020 Democratic primary
season. Specifically, they are trying to prop up the candidates of their choice — Joe Biden, Elizabeth Warren &amp; Pete Buttigieg —
while undermining Bernie Sander’s candidacy thru self-serving “poll”s.</p>

<p>Many of the pollsters use a statistically sound polling methodology,
which they then publish along with the results. We might disagree with the methodology (or) the
demographic selection, but we atleast have these details. Polls with these details are “somewhat”
legitimate.</p>

<p>No poll thats done in secrecy where all aspects are not open for public scrutiny
can be that that reliable, let alone accurate. This is not to say that no poll gives the general sense
of what people feel, but just that those polls where the pollsters have inherent self interest of the results
should not be taken seriously.</p>

<p>We now have a new phenomenon where a pollster that neither publishes their methodology,
nor demographics, but publishes just the summary/memo of which candidate
gets what percentage of votes. This memo is then picked-up by mainstream media to run
non-stop propaganda with no questions about the credibility of the poll.</p>

<p>This is the story of one such dubious organization — which is packed with establishment operatives —
that publishes polls that are highly questionable at best, outright corrupt at worst.</p>

<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>If you paid attention to news lately, you would notice media telling
everyone that <em>Bernie is falling</em> while <em>Warren is surging</em>.</p>

<p>To this end, I would like to focus on one of the recent polling published
by an organization called <strong>Focus on Rural America</strong>. I’ll refer to this organization as <em>FORA</em> from now on.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/PpollingNumbers/status/1174315218593341440" target="\_blank"><img src="images/twitter-political-polls-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Political Polls: Summary of Focus on Rural America" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>Here are some of the media outlets that picked the poll put out by <em>FORA</em>.</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/461896-new-poll-finds-biden-warren-in-virtual-tie-in-iowa" target="\_blank">New poll finds Biden, Warren in virtual tie in Iowa</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.politicususa.com/2019/09/18/iowa-democratic-poll.html" target="\_blank">New Iowa Poll Finds Warren Surging, Sanders Fading, and Biden Leading</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2019/sep/18/joe-biden-edges-elizabeth-warren-iowa-pete-buttigi/" target="\_blank">Joe Biden edges Elizabeth Warren in Iowa, Pete Buttigieg in third: Poll</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/462072-warren-shows-signs-of-broadening-her-base" target="\_blank">Warren shows signs of broadening her base</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.fox2detroit.com/news/presidential-candidate-amy-klobuchar-in-detroit-hoping-to-build-on-midwest-momentum" target="\_blank">Presidential candidate Amy Klobuchar in Detroit hoping to build on Midwest momentum</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2019/08/20/democratic-primary-rural-outreach-1469005" target="\_blank">Dems fear another rural wipeout will reelect Trump</a></li>
</ol>

<p>There are lot more outlets that picked up this poll. To see all of them go <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=&quot;focus+on+rural+america&quot;&amp;tbm=nws" target="\_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>And some political commentators have already picked this stuff &amp; are spreading it among their followers.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/davidaxelrod/status/1174299432692719616" target="\_blank"><img src="images/david-axelrod.png" alt="Diagram: David Axelrod sharing FORA poll" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>Also, polling pundits like <em>Nate Silver</em> have used this poll as a base to undermine Bernie’s popularity — while singing priases of the <em>chosen one</em>, Elizabeth Warren.</p>

<p><a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/theres-a-better-case-for-a-top-2-than-a-top-3/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/nates-liver-digg-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Nate Silver downplaying Bernie in Iowa" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>Mainstream TV outlets like MSNBC already used these polls to draw inference about electability, drumming up propaganda.</p>

<p class="article-post"><iframe width="800" height="600" class="featured-image margin-auto" src="https://streamable.com/uz9a4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p>I am told that many other mainstream TV outlets also ran multiple segments based on this specific poll. I will update this post when I gets access to the footage.</p>

<p>Since many legitimate media outlets &amp; TV talking heads are taking this poll seriously to push an agenda, lets take a close look at the organization.</p>

<h2 id="uncovering-the-actors">Uncovering the actors</h2>

<p>Lets start with analyzing the credibility of this poll publisher <em>FORA</em>; specifically,</p>

<ol>
  <li>Who are behind it</li>
  <li>Which pollster do they use</li>
  <li>What polling methodology does the pollster use</li>
</ol>

<p>If you go to <a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/190914-iowa-voter-survey-memo/" target="\_blank">this link</a>, You would notice that the poll is published by someone named <em>Jeff Link</em>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/190914-iowa-voter-survey-memo/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/iowa-voter-survey-summary-page-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Focus on America Summary page" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>When you click on the Author’s link, you get <em>The page you requested could not be found</em>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/author/jeff/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/jeff-not-found-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Jeff does not exists" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/about/" target="\_blank">About</a> &amp; <a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/contact-us/" target="\_blank">Contact</a> page does not help us either.</p>

<p>A different page on the website explains that <em>Jeff Link</em> is the co-founder of <em>FORA</em>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/2019/09/18/september-2019-poll-results/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/jeff-mention-in-fora-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Jeff Link is the co-founder of FORA" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>Navigating the website does not give you anymore information about who this man is.
If you google for his name, you will find another website called <a href="http://www.linkstrategies.com/our-team/jeff-link/" target="\_blank">Link strategies</a>.</p>

<p>It describes him as someone with expertise in <em>paid media strategy</em> &amp; <em>public opinion-research</em>.
He was <em>ex-Bill Clinton</em> staffer &amp; also ran <em>Paid Media and Research to the Obama for America Campaign</em> —
specifically — <em>he coordinated all paid media and polling in 25 states</em>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.linkstrategies.com/our-team/jeff-link/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/jeff-link-strategies-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Jeff Link - Link strategies" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>The same post also mentions another person who holds the post of chair in <em>FORA</em>, namely <strong>Patty Judge</strong> who also happens to be <em>Past Lt. Governor and Secretary of Agriculture</em> for Iowa.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/2019/09/18/september-2019-poll-results/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/patty-in-fora-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Patty Judge is the Chair of FORA" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p><em>Patty Judge</em> gave glowing views of <em>Elizabeth Warren</em> in Jan 2019 — a month after warren announced her candidacy for Democratic primary.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.macleans.ca/politics/washington/elizabeth-warren-haunted-by-ghosts-of-sexism-past/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/patty-praising-warren-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Patty Judge praising Warren" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>Not just that, as recently as Jun 2019, she hung around warren during her visit to an ethanol factory in Iowa.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/2019/06/13/warren-judge-tour-ethanol-plant/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/warren-and-patty-on-field-trip-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Patty Judge accompanying Warren" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>Going over the past posts further gives a glimpse of who else are behind <em>FORA</em>.</p>

<p>A post dating back to May 2017 lists a man named <strong>Sam Roecker</strong> as an Advisor.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/2017/05/30/new-nonprofit-seeks-boost-progressive-causes-rural-america/" target="\_blank"><img src="images/sam-roecker-in-fora-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Sam Roecker in FORA" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>His twitter profile says he worked as the state director for <strong>John Hickenlooper</strong> —
the same <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/videos/politics/2019/07/30/cnn-democratic-debate-bernie-sanders-john-hickenlooper-trump-vpx.cnn" target="\_blank"><em>throw your hands up</em> Hickenlooper</a>
who was after Bernie in the recent presidential polls before <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/john-hickenlooper-withdraw-2020-presidential-race-1454440" target="\_blank">dropping out</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/SamRoecker" target="\_blank"><img src="images/sam-roecker-twitter-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Sam Roecker in Twitter" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>In summary, here are the people behind <em>FORA</em>.</p>

<ol>
  <li>A co-founder, who worked for many Democratic establishment candidates in the past — Clinton, Obama &amp; more</li>
  <li>An advisor, who in the past worked for primary opponent of Bernie (Hickenlooper)</li>
  <li>A chairman, who praises Warren (another opponent of Bernie) &amp; hangs around with her during the current primary campaign</li>
</ol>

<p>Even with all the establishment actors running the show, its possible that the poll published by them might still be a <em>credible</em> one — if the pollster conducted the poll in a scientific manner with a well defined methodology.</p>

<p>So, lets look at the pollster &amp; the polling methodology he employed to arrive at this “poll”.</p>

<h2 id="uncovering-the-pollster">Uncovering the pollster</h2>

<p>On the last page of the <a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/190914-Iowa-Voter-Survey-memo.pdf" target="\_blank">memo</a>,
it is mentioned that a pollster named <strong>David Binder Research</strong> has conducted these polls.
We will get back to the pollster lil later.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/190914-Iowa-Voter-Survey-memo.pdf" target="\_blank"><img src="images/fora-methodology-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Sam Roecker in Twitter" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>We are only given access to the <a href="http://www.focusonruralamerica.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/190914-Iowa-Voter-Survey-memo.pdf" target="\_blank">memo</a> of the poll —
from which — it is hard to get any idea about what questions were actually posed to the voters &amp; what their answers were.</p>

<p>You are told vague things like</p>

<ol>
  <li>Percent with Positive Opinion</li>
  <li>Ruled Out <em>vs</em> Actively Considering</li>
</ol>

<p>They dont tell you how these voting percentages were arrived at —
how voters were selected — what their demographics are —
white/black/asian/native american, men/women, rich/middle class/working poor, old/middle aged/young —
what percentage of the potential voters were contacted over landline vs mobile.</p>

<p>Nothing. You get no details about these important factors.</p>

<p>They simply have a four page memo, which has tables that says this is what we found.
Almost all polls atleast give detailed breakdown, sampling criteria,
but this one does not even bother giving you that information.</p>

<p>It just shares the conclusions on what percentage of votes each of democratic primary candidate will get in Iowa.</p>

<p>Now lets get back to finding who is behind <em>David Binder Research</em>.</p>

<p>As per <a href="https://www.realclearpolitics.com/lists/hispanic_pollsters/david_binder.html" target="\_blank">Real clear politics</a>, <em>David Binder Research</em> is run by a guy
named <em>David Binder</em>, who worked as an <em>in-house pollster for the Obama campaign in 2008 and 2012</em>.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.realclearpolitics.com/lists/hispanic_pollsters/david_binder.html" target="\_blank"><img src="images/david-binder-on-rcp-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: David Binder in RCP" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>The most important aspect being</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Binder specializes in <strong>qualitative</strong> rather than <strong>quantitative</strong> research.
His focus is on assessing <strong>subjective factors</strong> such as <strong>language</strong>, <strong>emotion</strong>, and <strong>attitudes</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>To me, all this word salad means only one thing.
He <em>mind-reads</em> potential voters when conducting his polling.
In simple terms, his polls capture <em>his fellings</em> about <em>voter’s feelings</em> about politicians.</p>

<p>I have never heard a worse way to describe a pollster than this.
Given that only the memo is published without the underlying dataset,
I am assuming that this poll is based on the <strong>feelings</strong> of <em>David Binder</em> staff
about which democratic candidate gets what percentage of votes in Iowa
in the upcoming democratic primary election.</p>

<p>Also, when I looked at the staff page of <em>David Binder Research</em>, one of the name caught my eye.
His name is <em>Ethan Axelrod</em>.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.db-research.com/#team" target="\_blank"><img src="images/ethan-axelrod-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Ethan Axelrod in DBR" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<p>He is the son of <em>David Axelrod</em>, who happen to be the <a href="https://harris.uchicago.edu/directory/david-axelrod"><em>senior strategist for Obama’s presidential campaigns, served as senior advisor to Obama</em></a> &amp;
is a senior political commentator of CNN. He is also the host of a show called <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/shows/axe-files-david-axelrod">The Axe Files with David Axelrod</a> on CNN.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=David+Axelrod+children" target="\_blank"><img src="images/ethan-axelrod-parentage-highlight.png" alt="Diagram: Ethan Axelrod parentage" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></a></p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>An organization called <em>Focus on Rural America</em> —
that’s founded by someone who worked for Bill Clinton, ran paid campaigns for  Obama —
that’s advised by someone who worked as State director for Hickenlooper —
that’s chaired by someone who has apparent allegiance to one of the Democratic primary candidates —
specifically — Elizabeth Warren — publish just memo of the poll where Bernie is getting lower vote share than <em>Pete Buttigieg</em>.</p>

<p>These polls are conducted by ex-Obama pollster —
with a staff member whose father worked for Obama as chief strategist —
publishes just memo of the poll —
with numbers that are complete outliers —
with no information on the methodology/demographic breakdown —
which then are picked-up by mainstream media —
use this poll to push free propaganda for Warren &amp; other corporate dems —
while undermining Bernie’s campaign —
till this propaganda becomes reality in the minds of undecided voters.</p>

<p>Most outlets that reported on this poll did not mention that — the
polling is done by people who worked for corporate democrats in the past —
is commissioned by people who are currently batting for Warren —
a candidate in the current democratic primary.</p>

<p>What else do you call this other than <em>Manufacturing Consent</em> by democratic establishment —
in connivance with their toadies in the mainstream media —
to push a corporate democratic candidate?</p>

<h2 id="credits">Credits</h2>

<p>Thanks to the following people for sharing some of the references used in this article</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://twitter.com/greg06897" target="\_blank">Greg C</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://twitter.com/Clarknt67" target="\_blank">Clark</a></li>
</ul>

          ]]>
          
        </description>
        
        
        <media:content medium="image" url="https://thekalinga.in/2019/09/20/manufatucturing-consent/voted.jpeg" />
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://thekalinga.in/2019/09/20/manufatucturing-consent/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thekalinga.in/2019/09/20/manufatucturing-consent/</guid>
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
        <category>Bernie Sanders</category>
        
        <category>Democratic Party</category>
        
        <category>Focus on Rural America</category>
        
        <category>Fake polls</category>
        
        <category>Manufacturing consent</category>
        
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Consistency thru compensation in micro services</title>
        <description>
          
          
          <![CDATA[
            <img src="https://thekalinga.in/2019/03/22/consistency-thru-compensation-in-micro-services/consistency-failures.jpg" alt="Consistency thru compensation in micro services" >
            <p><img src="consistency-failures.jpg" alt="Consistency thru compensation in micro services" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<p>This article addresses the eventual consistency aspect of transactions in micro services environment where a transaction spans more than one micro service &amp; transaction failure midway is imminent</p>

<h2 id="existing-business-usecase">Existing business usecase</h2>

<p>Suppose that we currently have a monolithic order management system that is backed by a RDBMS</p>

<h3 id="business-requirements">Business requirements</h3>

<p>Our business expects us to give them the following guarantees</p>

<ol>
  <li>Never accept an order if the inventory does not have enough stock</li>
  <li>Every item in the inventory is either assigned to an order (or) available for further purchases by customer within a reasonable amount of time</li>
</ol>

<p>As every seasoned developer knows, Monolith is a heaven for systems that want consistency because of RDBMS &amp; the ACID guarantees it provides. But this comes at the cost of autonomy &amp; scalability</p>

<p>Because of ACID guarantees, when we update both order &amp; inventory tables, either the transaction succeeds (or) fails atomically. Because of this, it is easy to ensure</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Total inventory</strong> = <strong>Amount of stock left in inventory</strong> + <strong>quantity used up by previous orders</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>In essence, its relatively easy to fulfill this requirement in our monolithic world since we will be working against a single database</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Please note that most of the businesses will be OK if we oversell items even when we don’t have corresponding stock in the inventory. This is because once the order is placed, the business can ask vendors to send it more stock of the oversold items &amp; still fulfill our customer’s order. The point this article addresses is “can the technology live within business constraints”?. Suppose our business does not permit overselling because we are selling rare items, say classic paintings/some other exclusive items, which means we cant oversell as no other vendor can supply additional stock of all items in our inventory</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="breaking-monolith">Breaking monolith</h2>

<p>Suppose we chose micro services for achieving autonomy in terms of scalability/development velocity/release schedule, e.t.c, it follows that we can’t share a single database across all of these micro services. Sharing database across micro services forces each team to coordinate with other team as soon as database schema needs to change, which defeats the whole purpose of micro services</p>

<p>Each type of micro service (can have any number of instances) will have to have its own private datastore. In other words, multiple instances of the same service type share a single database, but this database is never shared across micro services</p>

<p>After we identified our <a href="https://martinfowler.com/bliki/BoundedContext.html">bounded contexts</a>, we came up with the following breakup of our monolith into two micro services namely</p>

<ol>
  <li><code>order-service</code> whose responsibility it is to accept customer orders</li>
  <li><code>inventory-service</code> whose responsibility it is to allow changes to inventory by both order service &amp; also by our own internal inventory team</li>
</ol>

<p><img src="svg-optimized/inventory-services-with-actors-and-db.svg" alt="Diagram: Inventory services with db &amp; actors" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<p>At first glance, fulfilling this business requirements in micro services does not look that hard</p>

<p>We can make <code>order-service</code> call to <code>inventory-service</code> to check if sufficient stock exists to fulfil the order. If stock is available, reduce the given quantity of stock &amp; permit the order to go thru. If not, deny the order</p>

<p><img src="svg-optimized/order-placement-sequence-diagram.svg" alt="Diagram: Order placement sequence" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<p>But any seasoned developer will tell you it is not that simple (and I would not have written this article if it was this simple)</p>

<h2 id="problem-with-concurrent-transactions">Problem with concurrent transactions</h2>

<p>Suppose two different users try purchasing the same item simultaneously when not enough stock exists to fulfill both the orders. If proper care is not taken at <code>inventory-service</code> level, we might allow both orders to succeed, even tho we don’t have enough stock to fulfill both</p>

<p><img src="svg-optimized/inventory-overdraw.svg" alt="Diagram: Inventory overdraw" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<p>As any one who is familiar with concurrency control will tell us, why doesn’t <code>inventory-service</code> reject the second request by utilizing <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Optimistic_concurrency_control">optimistic concurrency control</a> (or) <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/marcelolr/2010/07/16/optimistic-and-pessimistic-concurrency-a-simple-explanation/">pessimistic concurrency control</a></p>

<p>Once we apply this fix, if two users attempt simultaneous purchase only one of them would succeed if fulfilling both orders results in stock becoming negative</p>

<p><img src="svg-optimized/order-placement-sequence-diagram-singleshot-update.svg" alt="Diagram: Sequence diagram of Inventory service with optimistic concurrency control" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<h2 id="problem-with-server-failures">Problem with server failures</h2>

<p>Even with the above solution, we are still left with a problem</p>

<p>When it comes to servers on which our application runs, no one can guarantee that the hardware never fails. So server failure is a given. Every application must keep this in mind &amp; should be resilient to these failures</p>

<p>What if <code>inventory-service</code> reduced the quantity in its database &amp; <code>order-service</code> dies before it commits to its database?</p>

<p><img src="svg-optimized/order-server-fail-sequence-diagram.svg" alt="Diagram: Inventory server dies before local commit after inventory is reduced" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<p>Now we are left with an interesting situation where we have missing inventory from the system because the server crashed. Welcome to <strong>DATA INCONSISTENCY</strong></p>

<h2 id="going-back-to-drawing-board">Going back to drawing board</h2>

<p>Now we know business will be really unhappy because even though we have unsold physical inventory, its missing in the software because one of our server crashed in the middle of the transaction</p>

<p>There are multiple ways this problem can be addressed. In this article I will present one way of addressing this</p>

<p>In the previous approach, <code>order</code> will be either in <code>confirmed</code>/<code>rejected</code> state &amp; the client is stateless</p>

<p>But in our new approach</p>

<ol>
  <li>Order will have three states namely <code>initialized</code>, <code>confirmed</code> &amp; <code>rejected</code></li>
  <li>And our client would be Stateful</li>
  <li>In addition, the client will follow <a href="https://www.theserverside.com/news/1365146/Redirect-After-Post">Redirect after POST</a> pattern</li>
</ol>

<p>The reason for this redirect is because when client encounters a failure like the one in previous scenario, we don’t want the client to retry the operation &amp; place multiple orders for the same cart because user refreshed his browser. The previous pattern avoids this situation completely</p>

<p>Given that, here is our new approach</p>

<ol>
  <li>As soon as a request is received, <code>order-service</code> saves an order with status <code>initialized</code> to its own db</li>
  <li>Immediately, <code>order-service</code> will make call to <code>inventory-service</code> with the <code>&lt;order id&gt;</code> and additional item info to reduce the stock in a background thread with an exclusive <a href="https://www.percona.com/blog/2018/10/16/postgresql-locking-part-1-row-locks/">row level lock</a> on the newly created order</li>
  <li><code>order-service</code> responds to the client with HTTP <code>202 Accepted</code> (if API based client)/<code>302 Found</code> (if browser) response with a link to check the status of the order thru http <code>Location</code> header</li>
  <li>If background order placement succeeds, <code>order-service</code> will update the status of the order to <code>confirmed</code> &amp; releases row level lock on the order</li>
  <li>If not, <code>order-service</code> will update the status of the order to <code>rejected</code> &amp; releases row level lock on the order</li>
  <li>Once client sees above <code>202</code>/<code>302</code> response, it will redirect the user to order status page (incase of browser) so that browser refreshes does not cause duplicate orders. Its a best practice to show loading screen while the order is being processed</li>
  <li>Finally, <code>order-service</code> would respond to the order status request with <code>initialized</code>/<code>confirmed</code>/<code>rejected</code> status</li>
  <li>If the order is not yet concluded, latest status can be obtained by client using polling/server can implement <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Push_technology">long polling</a> to avoid client putting too much polling load</li>
</ol>

<p>From point <code>(2)</code> of the mechanism above, in normal flow, <code>order-service</code> takes an <code>exclusive row level lock</code> over the order row and releases only once the transaction is concluded</p>

<p>If server crashes in the middle, this lock on that order row would be be released immediately by database</p>

<p>We will use this aspect to make sure that we dont interfere with the transactions that are currently in progress, when we try to reconcile/compensate (will be discussed later)</p>

<p>Now back to the crash issue in <code>order-service</code></p>

<p>Since crash leaves our data in inconsistent state, <code>order-service</code> will have to explicitly <strong>reconcile</strong>/<strong>compensate</strong> for these failures at the application level by fetching the latest status of the order from <code>inventory-service</code> for abandoned orders. This is why its called <code>Compensating Transaction</code></p>

<p>Compensation guarantees order status to be consistent with the business rules <strong>EVENTUALLY</strong>, but not immediately</p>

<p>Depending on how soon we want this reconciliation, we can implement reconciliation in the following three stages</p>

<ol>
  <li>Startup reconciliation: Orders abandoned before the instance is started are guaranteed to be consistent once the instance is up (optional)</li>
  <li>On demand reconciliation: Orders requested by client are guaranteed to be consistent once the request is processed successfully (optional)</li>
  <li>Scheduled reconciliation: Orders that are abandoned before the scheduler ran are guaranteed to be consistent once scheduler runs successfully (mandatory)</li>
</ol>

<p>The guarantees each of the above three reconcilers provides are only valid for those orders for which the reconciler can acquire exclusive lock. If some other instance’s reconciler is doing compensation for any given order, the current reconciler just skips over them</p>

<p>Now lets look at each one of these options &amp; how the reconcilation/compensation works</p>

<h3 id="startup-reconciliation">Startup reconciliation</h3>

<p>This type of reconciliation guarantees that all the orders that were abandoned before the startup of the instance are guaranteed to be consistent once application is up</p>

<p>Suppose that <code>order-service</code> crashed in the middle of a transaction (abandoned). Instance can be brought back online manually/using kubernetes/some other mechanism</p>

<p>Here is what we should do as part of <code>order-service</code> startup to meet above guarantee</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>order-service</code> have to check if there are any orders in <code>initialized</code> state</li>
  <li>Attempt to acquire exclusive row level lock on each of the above orders. If lock cannot be acquired, just skip over it as this order is current being processed by some other instance</li>
  <li>For each of the above order on which lock can be acquired, <code>order-service</code> will request <code>inventory-service</code> about the latest status of the stock consumed by the given <code>&lt;order id&gt;</code></li>
  <li><code>inventory-service</code> will return latest status, which <code>order-service</code> will use to update in its own database &amp; release exclusive row level lock</li>
</ul>

<p>This way, <code>order-service</code> guarantees all orders that were abandoned before the startup will be consistent after startup</p>

<p><img src="svg-optimized/startup-reconciliation.svg" alt="Diagram: Starup reconciliation" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<h3 id="on-demand-reconciliation">On demand reconciliation</h3>

<p>Implementing this gives a guarantee that any abandoned order/transaction will be reconciled on the subsequent status request for that given order. Note that this only reconciles one specific order, not all abandoned orders</p>

<p>The way this works is, as soon as we receive a request for order status</p>

<ol>
  <li><code>order-service</code> will get the status of the order from local db</li>
  <li>If status is <code>initialized</code>, attempt to acquire exclusive row level lock</li>
  <li>If row level lock cannot be acquired (some other instance is working on this), then wait till exclusive row level lock can be acquired on the order</li>
  <li>Once lock is acquired, check if status is still <code>initialized</code>. If true, move to step (5), else return latest status</li>
  <li><code>order-service</code> will request <code>inventory-service</code> about the latest status of the stock consumed by the given <code>&lt;order id&gt;</code></li>
  <li><code>inventory-service</code> will return latest status, which <code>order-service</code> will use to update in its own database &amp; release exclusive row level lock</li>
</ol>

<p>Suppose that we have two instances of <code>order-service</code> &amp; the 1st instance is handling the order request &amp; the server crashed midway just like before. When the client resends order status request (clients are expected to do this on a best effort basis), it will be received by the second instance, at which point, we can do compensation logic for the abandoned order as part of this request. This way client does not have to wait till the scheduled reconciliation to get the latest status (next section)</p>

<p><img src="svg-optimized/sibling-reconciliation.svg" alt="Diagram: Sibling reconciliation" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<h3 id="scheduled-reconciliation">Scheduled reconciliation</h3>

<p>This type of reconciliation guarantees that all the orders that were abandoned before the start of the current run of scheduler are guaranteed to be consistent once scheduler run is complete</p>

<p>Since relying on client to reconcile all orders that failed midway is not a good idea as the client might never be able to contact the server due to network issue or some other reason, we want a mechanism within the application itself that does auto reconciliation at regular interval. This is where scheduled reconciliation comes in</p>

<p>At regular interval we have to <a href="https://docs.spring.io/spring/docs/current/spring-framework-reference/integration.html#scheduling">schedule a task</a> to be run within our application that does the reconciliation</p>

<p>For each run of the scheduled task, this is what the reconciler does</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>order-service</code> will fetch all orders that are in <code>initialized</code> state</li>
  <li>Attempt to acquire exclusive row level lock on each of the above orders. If lock cannot be acquired, just skip over it as this order is current being processed by some other instance</li>
  <li>For each of the above order on which lock can be acquired, <code>order-service</code> will request <code>inventory-service</code> about the latest status of the stock consumed by the given <code>&lt;order id&gt;</code></li>
  <li><code>inventory-service</code> will return latest status, which <code>order-service</code> will use to update in its own database &amp; release exclusive row level lock</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="svg-optimized/scheduled-reconciliation.svg" alt="Diagram: Scheduled reconciliation" class="featured-image img-fluid margin-auto" /></p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>We looked at one approach by which we can achieve resiliency in our application even under server crashes &amp; any intermediate failures</p>

<p>In order to achieve that, we needed</p>

<ol>
  <li>Stateful client</li>
  <li>Compensating transactions/Reconcilers at various levels</li>
</ol>

<p>We looked at three types of reconciliations</p>

<ul>
  <li>Startup reconciliation</li>
  <li>On demand reconciliation</li>
  <li>Scheduled reconciliation</li>
</ul>

<p>It is important to note that each application must have Scheduled reconciler as this guarantees regular reconciliation &amp; is not dependent on external actors. The other two types of reconciliations are optional but preferred</p>

<p>In a typical application, you would have all three reconcilers to reduce the amount of time the system will be in inconsistent state in case of unexpected failures</p>

<p>If you have any queries/suggestions let me know in the comments section</p>

          ]]>
          
        </description>
        
        
        <media:content medium="image" url="https://thekalinga.in/2019/03/22/consistency-thru-compensation-in-micro-services/consistency-failures.jpg" />
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://thekalinga.in/2019/03/22/consistency-thru-compensation-in-micro-services/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thekalinga.in/2019/03/22/consistency-thru-compensation-in-micro-services/</guid>
        
        <category>DDD</category>
        
        <category>Domain Driven Design</category>
        
        <category>Micro Services</category>
        
        <category>Distributed Systems</category>
        
        
        <category>Micro Services</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Inkscape Iconset: Pipes and Valves</title>
        <description>
          
          
          <![CDATA[
            <img src="https://thekalinga.in/2018/10/04/iconset-inkscape-pipes-and-valves/pipes-and-valves.svg" alt="Inkscape Iconset: Pipes and Valves" >
            <p><img src="pipes-and-valves.svg" alt="Inkscape Iconset: Pipes and Valves" class="featured-image img-fluid" /></p>

<p>Pipe &amp; Valve Iconset created using <a href="https://inkscape.org/en/">Inkscape</a></p>

<p>You can download them <a href="pipes-and-valves.svg">here</a></p>

<p>Licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">Public Domain Dedication</a></p>

          ]]>
          
        </description>
        
        
        <media:content medium="image" url="https://thekalinga.in/2018/10/04/iconset-inkscape-pipes-and-valves/pipes-and-valves.svg" />
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://thekalinga.in/2018/10/04/iconset-inkscape-pipes-and-valves/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thekalinga.in/2018/10/04/iconset-inkscape-pipes-and-valves/</guid>
        
        <category>Icon</category>
        
        <category>Inkscape</category>
        
        <category>CC0</category>
        
        <category>Pipe</category>
        
        <category>Valve</category>
        
        
        <category>Icons</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
